hey everybody welcome to this b1
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
teenagers
this is a really relevant topic because
all of us were teenagers once
or if you're really young you'll be a
teenager at some point
we're going to talk about some of the
good things about being a teenager
and some of the not so good things
before we get to the cons
let's kick things off with the pros the
first positive thing about being a
teenager
is that you're on your way to becoming
an adult this goes without saying
but kids normally dream about being
grown up
as a kid i'd constantly daydream about
what life was going to be like as an
adult
of course as a teenager you're not quite
there yet but you can see it approaching
adulthood starts seeming like a reality
and not just some distant future idea
it's pretty exciting right another cool
thing about being a teenager
is learning new things as kids a lot of
concepts or ideas are beyond our grasp
but as we get a little older we start to
understand these things
for example teenagers can delve deeper
into subjects like
economics business sociology and tons of
other things
i remember that i first started learning
about government
and politics during my teenage years i
also remember my writing skills
improving a lot when i was at that age
and even now when i look back on some of
my old writing
i don't find it that bad how about you
do you feel like you learned a lot as a
teenager
another positive thing that results from
adolescence is that you get
stronger physically to be honest this is
one of my favorite things about getting
older
i started hitting the weights when i was
about 16 and i became obsessed with
working out
this is a phase that a lot of teenagers
go through during their last couple
years of high school
i was fascinated by the fact that i was
able to lift more and more weight
and that i could get bigger and stronger
this is every boy's dream right
nowadays i'm not that big and strong
anymore and i can barely find the
motivation to do a home workout a few
times a week
okay one more positive thing about being
a teenager
is that you can start driving of course
in most countries you can't drive until
you're about 18 or so
but in the us you can get your license
when you're 16
and not only that but you can also get
your driving permit when you're only 15
and a half
just like i did when you have your
permit you're allowed to drive with your
parents in the car
which is still cool considering the fact
that you're not even 16
yet one of the most memorable days of my
youth was the first day i drove to
school in my own car
after i got my license i thought i was
the coolest kid in the world
alright let's talk briefly about a few
of the negative aspects of being a
teenager
first and foremost puberty anyone who's
gone through puberty
knows that most of the time it's not fun
your body changes
your voice changes a bunch of things
change
and for me the absolute worst part of
puberty was having acne
i'm sure a lot of you had acne or still
have it
i still have acne even though i'm a full
grown man this is definitely one of the
most annoying things about puberty
another negative thing about being a
teenager is the academic
pressure when you're in high school
everyone tells you that these are the
most important years
academically speaking if you don't get
good grades and if you don't get good
scores on the standardized tests
you can't get into a good college
teenagers are well aware of this
and it can take its toll on them one
last thing that could be a negative for
some teenagers
is figuring out what they want to do in
life many adolescents have no idea what
kind of career they want
because they haven't really had any
experience working in any field
i changed my mind a few times about what
i wanted to do and many of my friends
did too
it can be stressful for a teenager to
think about this stuff
okay now i'm going to ask you three
questions about today's video
to check your comprehension write your
answers in a comment down below
number one how old was i when i started
going to the gym
number two at what age can you get your
driver's license in the u.s
and number three what happens if you get
bad grades in high school
all right before we go remember to
subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram for more english tips and
lessons
i'll see you next time
[Music]